For a really long time,
一直以来
I had two mysteries that were hanging over me.
有两个迷团一直困扰着我。
I didn't understand them
我无法理解它们，
and, to be honest, I was quite afraid to look into them.
而且说实话，我害怕深究它们。
The first mystery was, I'm 40 years old,
第一个谜团是，我40岁了，
and all throughout my lifetime, year after year,
在我一生中，年复一年，
serious depression and anxiety have risen,
严重的抑郁和焦虑症状
in the United States, in Britain,
在美国，英国等国家 不断浮现出来，
and across the Western world.
横扫整个西方世界。
And I wanted to understand why.
我想要搞清楚为什么。
Why is this happening to us?
为什么这开始发生在我们身上？
Why is it that with each year that passes,
为什么过去的每一年里，
more and more of us are finding it harder to get through the day?
我们越来越多人发现 更难以度过每一天？
And I wanted to understand this because of a more personal mystery.
我想要理解这个是因为 一个很私人的谜团。
When I was a teenager,
当我还是10来岁时，
I remember going to my doctor
我记得有一次去看医生，
and explaining that I had this feeling, like pain was leaking out of me.
说我总觉得浑身疼痛。
I couldn't control it,
我不能控制它，
I didn't understand why it was happening,
我不理解为什么它会出现，
I felt quite ashamed of it.
并且感到非常羞耻。
And my doctor told me a story
医生告诉我了一个
that I now realize was well-intentioned,
现在我意识到是出于好意的故事，
but quite oversimplified.
但太过于简化。
Not totally wrong.
并非全错。
My doctor said, "We know why people get like this.
我医生说，“我们知道 人们为什么会这样。
Some people just naturally get a chemical imbalance in their heads --
有些人的大脑很自然地 会发生一些化学失衡——
you're clearly one of them.
你显然是其中一个。
All we need to do is give you some drugs,
我们要做的就是给你开一些药，
it will get your chemical balance back to normal."
它就会把你的化学平衡 恢复正常。”
So I started taking a drug called Paxil or Seroxat,
所以我开始服用帕罗西汀 或类似的药物。
it's the same thing with different names in different countries.
一个东西在不同国家 有不同的名字。
And I felt much better, I got a real boost.
然后我感觉好了很多， 也受到了很大的鼓舞。
But not very long afterwards,
但随后不久，
this feeling of pain started to come back.
这种疼痛的感觉回来了。
So I was given higher and higher doses
所以我使用越来越高的剂量，
until, for 13 years, I was taking the maximum possible dose
直到后来的13年，
that you're legally allowed to take.
我都在服用法律允许的最高剂量。
And for a lot of those 13 years, and pretty much all the time by the end,
在这13年的大部分时候， 差不多一直到最后，
I was still in a lot of pain.
我仍然很痛苦。
And I started asking myself, "What's going on here?
我开始问自己，“这是怎么回事？”
Because you're doing everything
因为你按照主导文化所说的
you're told to do by the story that's dominating the culture --
做了所有的事情——
why do you still feel like this?"
为什么你仍然会有这样的感受？
So to get to the bottom of these two mysteries,
所以为了揭开这两个谜团的谜底，
for a book that I've written
为了我写的一本书，
I ended up going on a big journey all over the world,
我进行了一场环球旅行，
I traveled over 40,000 miles.
旅途超过4万英里。
I wanted to sit with the leading experts in the world
我想跟世界一流的专家坐在一起
about what causes depression and anxiety
讨论是什么引发了抑郁和焦虑，
and crucially, what solves them,
并且最重要的是： 有什么治愈方法，
and people who have come through depression and anxiety
以及那些经历过抑郁和焦虑的人
and out the other side in all sorts of ways.
是如何以各种方式走出来的。
And I learned a huge amount
我一路走来， 从我认识的那些，
from the amazing people I got to know along the way.
了不起的人身上学到了很多。
But I think at the heart of what I learned is,
但我认为 我所学到的最核心的是，
so far, we have scientific evidence
目前为止，科学依据能够证明
for nine different causes of depression and anxiety.
有9种不同的 引发抑郁和焦虑的原因。
Two of them are indeed in our biology.
其中两个确实是由于生理因素。
Your genes can make you more sensitive to these problems,
你的基因会让你 对这些问题更敏感，
though they don't write your destiny.
虽然它们不能决定你的命运。
And there are real brain changes that can happen when you become depressed
当你变得抑郁时， 你的大脑会发生实质的变化，
that can make it harder to get out.
让你更难摆脱出来。
But most of the factors that have been proven
但绝大部分被证实
to cause depression and anxiety
引发抑郁和焦虑的因素
are not in our biology.
跟我们的生理因素无关，
They are factors in the way we live.
而主要取决于我们的生活方式。
And once you understand them,
一旦你理解了它们，
it opens up a very different set of solutions
就能开启一套 非常不同的解决方案，
that should be offered to people
应该和化学抗抑郁药
alongside the option of chemical antidepressants.
一起提供给人们。
For example,
比如，
if you're lonely, you're more likely to become depressed.
如果你很孤独， 你很可能会变得抑郁。
If, when you go to work, you don't have any control over your job,
如果，当你工作时，你对 自己的工作没有控制权，
you've just got to do what you're told,
你得按照吩咐去做，
you're more likely to become depressed.
你就更可能变得抑郁。
If you very rarely get out into the natural world,
如果你很少接触自然世界，
you're more likely to become depressed.
你更可能变得抑郁。
And one thing unites a lot of the causes of depression and anxiety
有一件事情把所有 我所知道的抑郁和焦虑
that I learned about.
联系在一起。
Not all of them, but a lot of them.
不是所有，但很多。
Everyone here knows
这里每个人都知道，
you've all got natural physical needs, right?
你们都有自然的生理需求，对吧？
Obviously.
显然。
You need food, you need water,
你需要食物，你需要水，
you need shelter, you need clean air.
你需要住所，你需要干净的空气。
If I took those things away from you,
如果我拿走那些东西，
you'd all be in real trouble, real fast.
你们都会很快就陷入巨大的困境。
But at the same time,
但同时，
every human being has natural psychological needs.
每个人都有自然的心理需求，
You need to feel you belong.
你需要有归属感。
You need to feel your life has meaning and purpose.
你需要感到 你的生活有意义和目的。
You need to feel that people see you and value you.
你需要感到人们关注你并重视你。
You need to feel you've got a future that makes sense.
你需要感觉 你有一个有意义的未来。
And this culture we built is good at lots of things.
我们建立的这种文化 擅长很多事情。
And many things are better than in the past --
很多事情比过去好多了——
I'm glad to be alive today.
我很高兴生活在今天。
But we've been getting less and less good
但我们对满足这些
at meeting these deep, underlying psychological needs.
深层次的心理需求 越来越不擅长了。
And it's not the only thing that's going on,
这并不是唯一的原因，
but I think it's the key reason why this crisis keeps rising and rising.
但我认为是这场危机 不断升级的关键原因。
And I found this really hard to absorb.
我发现这很难理解。
I really wrestled with the idea
我真的很纠结于这个想法：
of shifting from thinking of my depression as just a problem in my brain,
把我的抑郁症 从一个仅仅是我大脑中的问题，
to one with many causes,
转变成一个有很多
including many in the way we're living.
成因的问题， 包括我们的生活方式。
And it only really began to fall into place for me
直到有一天，我前去采访一位
when one day, I went to interview a South African psychiatrist
名叫德里克·萨莫菲尔德的 南非精神病医生，
named Dr. Derek Summerfield.
我才真正明白了这一点。
He's a great guy.
他是个很棒的人。
And Dr. Summerfield happened to be in Cambodia in 2001,
2001年，萨莫菲尔德在柬埔寨，
when they first introduced chemical antidepressants
当时他们首次在那个国家
for people in that country.
为人们引入化学抗抑郁药。
And the local doctors, the Cambodians, had never heard of these drugs,
当地的柬埔寨医生 从没听过这些药物，
so they were like, what are they?
所以，他们问“这些是什么？”
And he explained.
于是他解释了。
And they said to him,
然后他们告诉他，
"We don't need them, we've already got antidepressants."
“我们不需要它们， 我们已经有抗抑郁药了。”
And he was like, "What do you mean?"
他问，“你指的是什么？”
He thought they were going to talk about some kind of herbal remedy,
他以为他们会谈及某种草药，
like St. John's Wort, ginkgo biloba, something like that.
比如圣约翰草，银杏叶之类的。
Instead, they told him a story.
反之，他们告诉他一个故事。
There was a farmer in their community who worked in the rice fields.
他们社区有个农民在稻田里干活。
And one day, he stood on a land mine
有天，他踩到了
left over from the war with the United States,
抗美战争时留下的地雷，
and he got his leg blown off.
他的腿被炸掉了。
So they him an artificial leg,
所以他们给他装了一只假腿，
and after a while, he went back to work in the rice fields.
不久之后他就回到稻田干活。
But apparently, it's super painful to work under water
但显然，你带着假腿
when you've got an artificial limb,
在水下干活非常痛疼，
and I'm guessing it was pretty traumatic
而且我猜他 回到腿被炸掉的地方干活
to go back and work in the field where he got blown up.
一定很痛苦。
The guy started to cry all day,
这个人开始整天哭泣，
he refused to get out of bed,
他拒绝下床，
he developed all the symptoms of classic depression.
他出现了所有 典型的抑郁症症状。
The Cambodian doctor said,
柬埔寨医生说，
"This is when we gave him an antidepressant."
“就在这时 我们给他开了抗抑郁药。”
And Dr. Summerfield said, "What was it?"
萨莫菲尔德医生问，“是什么药？”
They explained that they went and sat with him.
他们解释说， 他们过去跟他坐在一起。
They listened to him.
他们倾听他。
They realized that his pain made sense --
他们认识到他的痛苦合情合理——
it was hard for him to see it in the throes of his depression,
身处沮丧的阵痛中， 他本人很难看出这一点，
but actually, it had perfectly understandable causes in his life.
但确实，这是他生活中 完全可以理解的原因。
One of the doctors, talking to the people in the community, figured,
其中一个医生 和社区里的人交谈，想到，
"You know, if we bought this guy a cow,
“如果我们给这人买一头奶牛，
he could become a dairy farmer,
他就可以变成一个奶农了，
he wouldn't be in this position that was screwing him up so much,
他就不会处在这种境地， 把自己搞得如此狼狈了，
he wouldn't have to go and work in the rice fields."
他也不用去稻田里干活了。”
So they bought him a cow.
于是他们给他买了一头奶牛。
Within a couple of weeks, his crying stopped,
没几周，他停止了哭泣，
within a month, his depression was gone.
不到1个月，他的抑郁症消失了。
They said to doctor Summerfield,
他们跟萨莫菲尔德医生说，
"So you see, doctor, that cow, that was an antidepressant,
“所以你看，医生，那头奶牛， 就是抗抑郁药，
that's what you mean, right?"
那是你说的药吧？”
(Laughter)
（笑声）
(Applause)
（鼓掌）
If you'd been raised to think about depression the way I was,
如果你打小就和我一样 思考抑郁症，
and most of the people here were,
像座大多数人这样，
that sounds like a bad joke, right?
那听起来像个冷笑话，对吧？
"I went to my doctor for an antidepressant,
“我找医生开抗抑郁药，
she gave me a cow."
她给了我一头奶牛。”
But what those Cambodian doctors knew intuitively,
但那些柬埔寨人凭直觉就知道的、
based on this individual, unscientific anecdote,
基于这个个体的，不科学的轶事，
is what the leading medical body in the world,
是世界领先的医疗机构，
the World Health Organization,
世界卫生组织，
has been trying to tell us for years,
多年来， 基于最好的科学证据，
based on the best scientific evidence.
一直试图告诉我们的。
If you're depressed,
如果你抑郁，
if you're anxious,
如果你很焦虑，
you're not weak, you're not crazy,
你不是脆弱，你没有疯，
you're not, in the main, a machine with broken parts.
总的来说，你不是一个 零部件坏了的机器，
You're a human being with unmet needs.
你是个需求未被满足的人。
And it's just as important to think here about what those Cambodian doctors
在这里，思考柬埔寨医生说的
and the World Health Organization are not saying.
和世界卫生组织没说的同样重要。
They did not say to this farmer,
他们没跟这个农民说，
"Hey, buddy, you need to pull yourself together.
“嘿，伙计，你需要振作起来，
It's your job to figure out and fix this problem on your own."
你得自己解决和修复这个问题。”
On the contrary, what they said is,
相反，他们说的是，
"We're here as a group to pull together with you,
“我们作为一个团队 来和你一起努力，
so together, we can figure out and fix this problem."
所以一起，我们可以解决 和修复这个问题。”
This is what every depressed person needs,
这是每一个抑郁的人需要的，
and it's what every depressed person deserves.
并且也是 每一个抑郁的人应得的。
This is why one of the leading doctors at the United Nations,
这是为什么 有位联合国的顶尖医生，
in their official statement for World Health Day,
在2017年世界卫生日的
couple of years back in 2017,
官方宣言中写到，
said we need to talk less about chemical imbalances
我们要少谈化学失衡，
and more about the imbalances in the way we live.
多谈谈我们生活方式的失衡。
Drugs give real relief to some people --
药物对有些人 有真正的缓解作用——
they gave relief to me for a while --
它们对我有阵子也很有效——
but precisely because this problem goes deeper than their biology,
但因为这个问题 比他们的生物构造更深入，
the solutions need to go much deeper, too.
解决方案也需要更为深入。
But when I first learned that,
但当我第一次知道的时候，
I remember thinking,
我记得我在想，
"OK, I could see all the scientific evidence,
“我能看到所有的科学证据，
I read a huge number of studies,
我阅读了大量的研究，
I interviewed a huge number of the experts who were explaining this,"
我采访了很多专家来 解释这一问题，”
but I kept thinking, "How can we possibly do that?"
但我一直在想， “我们怎么可能做到？”
The things that are making us depressed
让我们抑郁的事情
are in most cases more complex than what was going on
在很多情况下比那个柬埔寨农民
with this Cambodian farmer.
远复杂得多。
Where do we even begin with that insight?
基于那个观点， 我们该从哪里下手呢？
But then, in the long journey for my book,
然而后来， 在我写书的漫长旅途中，
all over the world,
在全球旅行中，
I kept meeting people who were doing exactly that,
我不断遇到正在那样做的人，
from Sydney, to San Francisco,
从悉尼，到旧金山，
to São Paulo.
到圣保罗。
I kept meeting people who were understanding
我一直遇见理解引发
the deeper causes of depression and anxiety
抑郁和焦虑深层原因的人，
and, as groups, fixing them.
并且，作为群体，修复它们。
Obviously, I can't tell you about all the amazing people
显然，我不能告诉你们 我认识和写下的
I got to know and wrote about,
所有这些让人惊叹的人，
or all of the nine causes of depression and anxiety that I learned about,
或者所有我所习得的引发 抑郁和焦虑的9个原因，
because they won't let me give a 10-hour TED Talk --
因为他们不会让我做一个 10小时的TED演讲——
you can complain about that to them.
你们可以向他们抱怨。
But I want to focus on two of the causes
但如果可以的话， 我想聚焦在两个原因，
and two of the solutions that emerge from them, if that's alright.
以及对应的两个解决方案。
Here's the first.
这是第一个。
We are the loneliest society in human history.
我们处于人类历史上 最孤独的社会。
There was a recent study that asked Americans,
最近研究有一项研究，询问美国人
"Do you feel like you're no longer close to anyone?"
“你感觉不再跟任何人亲近了吗？”
And 39 percent of people said that described them.
39%的人说这描述符合他们。
"No longer close to anyone."
“不再跟任何人亲近。”
In the international measurements of loneliness,
在国际孤独测量评估中，
Britain and the rest of Europe are just behind the US,
英国和其他欧洲国家仅次于美国。
in case anyone here is feeling smug.
以防这里有人沾沾自喜。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
I spent a lot of time discussing this
我花了很多时间就孤独问题
with the leading expert in the world on loneliness,
和世界一流的专家交流。
an incredible man named professor John Cacioppo,
一个非常优秀的人， 约翰·卡奇奥波教授，
who was at Chicago,
他在芝加哥，
and I thought a lot about one question his work poses to us.
他的工作给我们提出了 一个问题，我想了很久。
Professor Cacioppo asked,
卡奇奥波教授问到，
"Why do we exist?
“我们为什么存在？
Why are we here, why are we alive?"
我们为什么在这儿， 我们为什么活着？”
One key reason
一个关键的原因在于
is that our ancestors on the savannas of Africa
我们非洲大草原上的祖先
were really good at one thing.
真的非常擅长一件事情。
They weren't bigger than the animals they took down a lot of the time,
他们不比很多时候 他们放倒的动物高大，
they weren't faster than the animals they took down a lot of the time,
他们不比很多时候 他们放倒的动物跑得更快，
but they were much better at banding together into groups
但他们更擅长抱团
and cooperating.
与协作。
This was our superpower as a species --
这是我们作为一个物种的超能力。
we band together,
我们聚集在一起，
just like bees evolved to live in a hive,
就像蜜蜂进化到住在蜂巢中一样，
humans evolved to live in a tribe.
人类进化到部落聚居。
And we are the first humans ever
而我们是第一批
to disband our tribes.
解散部落的人类。
And it is making us feel awful.
这让我们感到糟糕。
But it doesn't have to be this way.
但事情不一定非得这样。
One of the heroes in my book, and in fact, in my life,
我书中，也是我生活中的一个英雄，
is a doctor named Sam Everington.
是一个叫山姆·艾佛林顿的医生。
He's a general practitioner in a poor part of East London,
他是东伦敦贫民区的 一名全科医生，
where I lived for many years.
我在那生活过好多年。
And Sam was really uncomfortable,
山姆真的很不容易，
because he had loads of patients
因为很多病人
coming to him with terrible depression and anxiety.
都带着严重的抑郁和焦虑来找他。
And like me, he's not opposed to chemical antidepressants,
和我一样， 他不反对使用抗抑郁药，
he thinks they give some relief to some people.
他认为药物对一些人有缓解作用。
But he could see two things.
但他可以看到两件事情。
Firstly, his patients were depressed and anxious a lot of the time
第一，他的病人很多时候
for totally understandable reasons, like loneliness.
因为完全可以理解的理由 而抑郁和焦虑，比如说孤独。
And secondly, although the drugs were giving some relief to some people,
第二，尽管药物能给 部分人带来一些缓解。
for many people, they didn't solve the problem.
对多数人而言， 它们无法解决问题，
The underlying problem.
根本性的问题。
One day, Sam decided to pioneer a different approach.
一天，山姆决定 开创一种不同的方法。
A woman came to his center, his medical center,
一位女性来到他的医疗中心，
called Lisa Cunningham.
她叫丽莎·坎宁安。
I got to know Lisa later.
我后来才认识的。
And Lisa had been shut away in her home with crippling depression and anxiety
丽莎因为严重的抑郁和焦虑 被隔离家中，
for seven years.
长达7年。
And when she came to Sam's center, she was told, "Don't worry,
当她来到山姆的中心时， 她被告知，“不要担心，
we'll carry on giving you these drugs,
我们会继续给你这些药，
but we're also going to prescribe something else.
但我们也会开一些其他东西。
We're going to prescribe for you to come here to this center twice a week
你需要每周来这个中心两次，
to meet with a group of other depressed and anxious people,
去见其他抑郁和焦虑的人们，
not to talk about how miserable you are,
不是来说你有多么不幸，
but to figure out something meaningful you can all do together
而是找出一些你们可以 一起做的有意义的事情，
so you won't be lonely and you won't feel like life is pointless."
这样你就不会感到孤独， 或是生活没有意义。
The first time this group met,
这些人第一次见面时，
Lisa literally started vomiting with anxiety,
丽莎焦虑到开始呕吐，
it was so overwhelming for her.
因为这对她而言压力非常大。
But people rubbed her back, the group started talking,
不过人们开始给她按摩， 这群人开始聊天，
they were like, "What could we do?"
“我们能做什么？”
These are inner-city, East London people like me,
这些都是和我一样 住在伦敦东部贫民区的人，
they didn't know anything about gardening.
他们不懂园艺。
They were like, "Why don't we learn gardening?"
“为什么我们不学习园艺呢？”
There was an area behind the doctors' offices
医生办公室后面有块区域
that was just scrubland.
是个灌木丛。
"Why don't we make this into a garden?"
“我们为什么不把它 改造成花园呢？”
They started to take books out of the library,
于是他们开始从图书馆借书，
started to watch YouTube clips.
开始看YouTube视频。
They started to get their fingers in the soil.
他们开始把手伸进土里。
They started to learn the rhythms of the seasons.
他们开始学习四季的旋律。
There's a lot of evidence
有大量的研究表明
that exposure to the natural world
接触自然世界
is a really powerful antidepressant.
是一种非常有效的抗抑郁药。
But they started to do something even more important.
但他们开始做一些更重要的事情。
They started to form a tribe.
他们开始形成部落。
They started to form a group.
他们开始形成团队。
They started to care about each other.
他们开始关心彼此。
If one of them didn't show up,
如果其中有个人没出现，
the others would go looking for them -- "Are you OK?"
其他人会去寻找—— “你还好吗？”
Help them figure out what was troubling them that day.
帮助他们解决 他们那天遇到的麻烦。
The way Lisa put it to me,
就像丽莎向我说的，
"As the garden began to bloom,
“随着园中花朵的绽放，
we began to bloom."
我们也开始绽放。”
This approach is called social prescribing,
这个方法被称为社会处方，
it's spreading all over Europe.
它正在整个欧洲蔓延。
And there's a small, but growing body of evidence
有一个小的，但不断增长的证据
suggesting it can produce real and meaningful falls
表明它可以真正且有意义地
in depression and anxiety.
缓解抑郁和焦虑。
And one day, I remember standing in the garden
有天，我记得站在这个
that Lisa and her once-depressed friends had built --
丽莎和她那些一度抑郁的 朋友建造的花园中——
it's a really beautiful garden --
这真是个美丽的花园——
and having this thought,
我产生了这个想法，
it's very much inspired by a guy called professor Hugh Mackay in Australia.
很大程度上受到 澳大利亚的休·麦凯教授的启发。
I was thinking, so often when people feel down in this culture,
我在想，当人们 在这种文化中感到沮丧时，
what we say to them -- I'm sure everyone here said it, I have --
我们是怎么跟他们说的—— 我确信这里每个人这么说过，
we say, "You just need to be you, be yourself."
我也说过—— “你只要做自己，做你自己。”
And I've realized, actually, what we should say to people is,
我已经意识到，其实， 我们应该跟人们说的是，
"Don't be you.
“别自己一个人，
Don't be yourself.
不要做自己。
Be us, be we.
做我们，我们一起。
Be part of a group."
成为团队的一员。”
(Applause)
（鼓掌）
The solution to these problems
这些问题的解决方案
does not lie in drawing more and more on your resources
并不在于把更多的资源
as an isolated individual --
看作孤立个体——
that's partly what got us in this crisis.
这正是导致我们 陷入这场危机的部分原因。
It lies on reconnecting with something bigger than you.
它在于与比我们更大 的东西重新连接。
And that really connects to one of the other causes
这正是我想和你们说的
of depression and anxiety that I wanted to talk to you about.
另一个和抑郁及焦虑有关的成因。
So everyone knows
所以每个人都知道，
junk food has taken over our diets and made us physically sick.
垃圾食品已经占据了 我们的饮食，让我们身体不适。
I don't say that with any sense of superiority,
我说这话并不是带着优越感在说，
I literally came to give this talk from McDonald's.
我来做演讲之前刚去过麦当劳。
I saw all of you eating that healthy TED breakfast, I was like no way.
我看到你们都吃的那种 健康的TED早餐，我是不会吃的。
But just like junk food has taken over our diets and made us physically sick,
不过就像垃圾食品已经占据了 我们的饮食，并让我们身体不适，
a kind of junk values have taken over our minds
也有一类垃圾价值观 占据了我们的头脑，
and made us mentally sick.
并使我们精神染病。
For thousands of years, philosophers have said,
几千年来，哲学家们说过，
if you think life is about money, and status and showing off,
如果你认为生活是关于 金钱，地位和炫耀，
you're going to feel like crap.
你就会觉得自己像个废物。
That's not an exact quote from Schopenhauer,
这不是叔本华的原话，
but that is the gist of what he said.
但这是他所说的要点。
But weirdly, hardy anyone had scientifically investigated this,
但奇怪的是， 几乎没有人对此进行过研究，
until a truly extraordinary person I got to know, named professor Tim Kasser,
直到我认识了一个出色的人， 伊利诺斯州诺克斯学院
who's at Knox College in Illinois,
的提姆·卡瑟教授，
and he's been researching this for about 30 years now.
他现在已经研究 这个主题超过30年了。
And his research suggests several really important things.
他的研究 揭示了几个非常重要的事情。
Firstly, the more you believe
首先，你越相信
you can buy and display your way out of sadness,
你可以通过购物和炫耀 来摆脱悲伤，
and into a good life,
过上美好的生活，
the more likely you are to become depressed and anxious.
你更有可能变得抑郁和焦虑。
And secondly,
第二，
as a society, we have become much more driven by these beliefs.
作为一个社会， 我们越来越被这些信念驱动。
All throughout my lifetime,
我的一生，
under the weight of advertising and Instagram and everything like them.
都处在广告，Instagram 和类似东西的重压之下。
And as I thought about this,
当我想到这个的时候，
I realized it's like we've all been fed since birth, a kind of KFC for the soul.
我意识到这就像我们的灵魂一出生 就被喂了诸如肯德基一类的东西。
We've been trained to look for happiness in all the wrong places,
我们被训练 在错误的地方寻找幸福，
and just like junk food doesn't meet your nutritional needs
这就像垃圾食品 不能满足你的营养需求，
and actually makes you feel terrible,
并且实际上还让你感到糟糕一样，
junk values don't meet your psychological needs,
垃圾价值也不能满足你的精神需求，
and they take you away from a good life.
反而夺走了你的美好生活。
But when I first spent time with professor Kasser
当我第一次和卡塞尔碰面时，
and I was learning all this,
我学到了所有这些东西。
I felt a really weird mixture of emotions.
我真是百感交集。
Because on the one hand, I found this really challenging.
因为一方面，我觉得 这真的很有挑战性。
I could see how often in my own life, when I felt down,
我时常可以看到自己的生活中， 每当我跌倒，
I tried to remedy it with some kind of show-offy, grand external solution.
我试着用一些炫耀的， 宏大的外部解决方案来修补它。
And I could see why that did not work well for me.
我可以看到为什么那样对 我并不怎么见效。
I also thought, isn't this kind of obvious?
我也想到，这不是很明显吗？
Isn't this almost like banal, right?
这不是很老套吗？
If I said to everyone here,
如果我跟在座各位说，
none of you are going to lie on your deathbed
你们谁也不会在临终的病榻之上，
and think about all the shoes you bought and all the retweets you got,
想着自己买了多少双鞋， 收到了多少条转发，
you're going to think about moments
而是会想起你生命中
of love, meaning and connection in your life.
那些富有爱、意义和联系的瞬间。
I think that seems almost like a cliché.
我觉得这似乎是陈词滥调。
But I kept talking to professor Kasser and saying,
但我继续 和卡塞尔教授交谈，说道，
"Why am I feeling this strange doubleness?"
“为什么我会有这种 奇怪的双重感觉呢？”
And he said, "At some level, we all know these things.
他说，“某种程度上， 我们都知道这些东西。
But in this culture, we don't live by them."
但在这种文化中， 我们并不靠它们过活。”
We know them so well they've become clichés,
我们对它们实在太清楚了， 它们于是变得陈词滥调，
but we don't live by them.
但我们不靠它们过活。
I kept asking why, why would we know something so profound,
我一直在问自己为什么， 为什么我们知道有些东西很重要，
but not live by it?
但不靠它们而活？
And after a while, professor Kasser said to me,
过了一会，卡塞尔博士告诉我，
"Because we live in a machine
“因为我们生活在一台机器中，
that is designed to get us to neglect what is important about life."
它被设计成让我们忽略 生命中最重要的东西。”
I had to really think about that.
我真得好好想想。
"Because we live in a machine
“因为我们生活在一台机器中，
that is designed to get us to neglect what is important about life."
它被设计成让我们忽略 生命中最重要东西。”
And professor Kasser wanted to figure out if we can disrupt that machine.
卡塞尔教授想要搞清楚 我们能否打败那台机器。
He's done loads of research into this;
他为此做了很多研究。
I'll tell you about one example,
我会告诉你们一个例子，
and I really urge everyone here to try this with their friends and family.
我真的很迫切鼓励这里每个人 跟朋友和家人试试这个。
With a guy called Nathan Dungan, he got a group of teenagers and adults
我和Nathan Dungan一起， 他让一群青少年和成年人
to come together for a series of sessions over a period of time, to meet up.
在一段时间内一起参加 一系列的会议，互相见面。
And part of the point of the group
这个群体的一部分目的是
was to get people to think about a moment in their life
让人们回想他们生命中确实觉得
they had actually found meaning and purpose.
有意义和有目的的瞬间。
For different people, it was different things.
不同的人，想到的会是不同的东西。
For some people, it was playing music, writing, helping someone --
对有些人， 是播放音乐，写作，帮助别人——
I'm sure everyone here can picture something, right?
我相信这里每一位都能 想起一些事情，对吧？
And part of the point of the group was to get people to ask,
这个群体的部分目的 是让人们提问，
"OK, how could you dedicate more of your life
“好了，你怎么才能把 生命中更多的时间
to pursuing these moments of meaning and purpose,
用来追求这些有意义 和目的的时刻呢，
and less to, I don't know, buying crap you don't need,
并且少买一些你不需要的垃圾，
putting it on social media and trying to get people to go,
把它们发到社交媒体上， 并试图让别人说，
'OMG, so jealous!'"
“我的妈，真是拉仇恨！”
And what they found was,
他们的发现是，
just having these meetings,
只是通过这些会面，
it was like a kind of Alcoholics Anonymous for consumerism, right?
这有点像消费主义的 匿名戒酒会，对吧？
Getting people to have these meetings, articulate these values,
让人们参与这些会议， 阐明这些价值观，
determine to act on them and check in with each other,
并决定采取行动，互相监督，
led to a marked shift in people's values.
引发了人们价值观的显著转变。
It took them away from this hurricane of depression-generating messages
它把他们从训练我们 在错误的地方寻找幸福
training us to seek happiness in the wrong places,
和产生抑郁的飓风中带走，
and towards more meaningful and nourishing values
向着更有意义、更有营养的，
that lift us out of depression.
带领我们走出抑郁的价值前进。
But with all the solutions that I saw and have written about,
但所有我看到和写过的解决方案，
and many I can't talk about here,
很多我无法在这里讲，
I kept thinking,
我一直在思考，
you know: Why did it take me so long to see these insights?
为什么它花了我 那么长时间才看到这些洞见？
Because when you explain them to people --
因为当你向人们解释它们时——
some of them are more complicated, but not all --
有些东西更复杂， 但非全都复杂——
when you explain this to people, it's not like rocket science, right?
当你向人们解释这些， 这不是必定如此，对吧？
At some level, we already know these things.
在某种程度上， 我们已经知道这些东西。
Why do we find it so hard to understand?
为什么我们会发现它很难理解？
I think there's many reasons.
我认为这里有很多原因。
But I think one reason is that we have to change our understanding
但我认为有个原因是我们得改变
of what depression and anxiety actually are.
我们对抑郁和焦虑的认识。
There are very real biological contributions
抑郁和焦虑有非常真实
to depression and anxiety.
的生物学原因。
But if we allow the biology to become the whole picture,
但如果我们让生物学 成为唯一解释，
as I did for so long,
就如我很久以来那样做的，
as I would argue our culture has done pretty much most of my life,
我认为我们的文化在我生命的 大部分时间里都在起作用，
what we're implicitly saying to people is, and this isn't anyone's intention,
我们含蓄地告诉人们的是， 这不是任何人的本意，
but what we're implicitly saying to people is,
但我们含蓄地告诉人们的是，
"Your pain doesn't mean anything.
“你的痛疼不意味着什么。
It's just a malfunction.
它只是个故障。
It's like a glitch in a computer program,
就像电脑程序的一个小故障，
it's just a wiring problem in your head."
它只是你头脑中的线路问题。”
But I was only able to start changing my life
但直到我意识到抑郁 并不是一种故障，
when I realized your depression is not a malfunction.
我才能够开始改变我的生活。
It's a signal.
它是个信号。
Your depression is a signal.
你的抑郁是个信号。
It's telling you something.
它在告诉你一些东西。
(Applause)
（鼓掌）
We feel this way for reasons,
我们这样感受是有原因的，
and they can be hard to see in the throes of depression --
在抑郁的阵痛中很难看到它们——
I understand that really well from personal experience.
就我个人经验而言，我非常理解。
But with the right help, we can understand these problems
但有了正确的帮助， 我们能够理解这些问题
and we can fix these problems together.
并共同修复这些问题。
But to do that,
但要做到这一点，
the very first step
第一步是
is we have to stop insulting these signals
我们要停止侮辱这些信号，
by saying they're a sign of weakness, or madness or purely biological,
说它们是软弱的，疯狂的 或纯粹生理的信号，
except for a tiny number of people.
除了少数人。
We need to start listening to these signals,
我们需要倾听这些信号，
because they're telling us something we really need to hear.
因为它在告诉我们真的 需要去倾听的事情。
It's only when we truly listen to these signals,
只有当我们真正倾听这些信号，
and we honor these signals and respect these signals,
重视这些信号，尊重这些信号时，
that we're going to begin to see
我们才会看到
the liberating, nourishing, deeper solutions.
解放、滋养、深入的解决方案。
The cows that are waiting all around us.
奶牛在周围等着我们。
Thank you.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（鼓掌）